<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://www.stunthamster.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 17:01:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.stunthamster.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Life without Puppet</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.io/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.io/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been more than six months since I&amp;rsquo;ve written, commented on, or reviewed any Puppet code. This might come as a shock
for some folk, especially those who have read my book &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; INSERT LINK &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out of the way straight away;
It&amp;rsquo;s not because I think Puppet has suddenly become awful, because that&amp;rsquo;s patently absurd. Puppet is in use in some of
the largest companies, and is enjoying explosive growth. It&amp;rsquo;s more I&amp;rsquo;ve found a tool that fits my workflow and
philospohy better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with, and hacking on, Ansible. As it turns out, Ansible addresses many of the
frustrations that I&amp;rsquo;ve had with Puppet, and allows me to be far more productive, without sacrificing any of the power of
an ideopotent configuration managment tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first major advantage of Ansible over Puppet is it&amp;rsquo;s method of connection. Puppet uses a cetnralised server that
implements it&amp;rsquo;s own certificate store. It talks over its own TCP ports, and requires a fixed server to host the Puppet
Master. The agent has to be installed on each client, and enrolled with the Puppet Master. Ansible on the other hand c
an be run from your laptop, and uses SSH to connect to the clients, generally meaning that the firewall is already open,
or at the very least, is easy to open. Becuase it uses SSH, you can use the existing techniques to manage Key pairs for
security, and it requires no agent to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a huge, huge deal when your introducing a new tool into an organisation. Many organisations I have worked in have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ease-of-use:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Ease of use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible has some of the best documentation it&amp;rsquo;s been my disctinct pleasure to come across. From the getting started guide,
through to module usage, and custom development is all detailed; this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that Puppet is any slouch when it comes
to documentation, but there are elements which are less than obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flexibility:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuppetDB 2.1.0 Has Been Released</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.io/posts/puppetdb210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.io/posts/puppetdb210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s July, the sun is… Well, the sun is no where in site, but at least the PuppetDB chaps have given us some summer
cheer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PuppetDB 2.1.0 has been released, and it brings some cool new features for reporting, including a feature I thought was
sorely missing, the ability to filter reports via the Puppet status (I.e. succeeded, failed). This is fantastic, as
before this you could dive into the event data to find out what failed, but couldn’t approach it from the more logical
report endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes creating your own dashboard around PuppetDB substantially easier, and means that adhoc reporting should also
be a cinch using some simple Curls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly more exciting though, is the introduction of V4 of the PuppetDB query engine. Although touted as being somewhat
of a sanity saver for the PuppetDB dev (Which is a shame, I prefer my devs a little mad), it’s also fantastic for the
end user. Up until now, support for various operators has been either lacking, or non existent for certain endpoints,
and the introduction of new endpoints has been slow. This has been in part due to the, in the words of the dev, the
disjointed code base. With query engine V4 this is now a thing of the past, and should ensure that operators and
features should start to appear much more rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Stunt Hamster</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve managed to find the corner of the internet that Michael Duffy lives. Hello! That’s me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have gathered by a brief look at the blog posts, I’m a freelance Devops Engineer and writer. If you looked
at the front page and it’s empty, then I’ve either forgotten to upload the content, or I’m in the middle of yet another
redesign. It’s probably the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get to the heart of the matter, if your reading the about page, you probably want to know a little bit more about
me, and what it is I do. Let’s take a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps consultancy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been practicing a methodology akin to ‘DevOps’ before it became a buzzword that all the cool kids want to use.
Essentially, this means that I’ve been an embedded systems administrator in many different development teams, and
worked with those fine fellows to both improve the delivered product, and to smooth the deployment process. My roles
generally take in everything from full stack automation, through to infrastructure design and architecture. I’ve worked
for companies such as Telefonica O2 and BskyB, through to small startups, and can quite happily work with, and manage
projects that are budgeted from anywhere from fifty million pounds through to fifty pence. Some of the projects I’ve
worked on have been the design, implementation and automation of the infrastructure powering the online search features
of the Sky set top box (Over three million connected clients), the automation of the o2.co.uk web pages
(Including several iPhone launches, AKA a DDOS in a box), and the implementation of DevOps practices at several startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy working within Agile development teams, but equally, have worked with people who pray to the altar of
prince 2 methodology; As long as your project is interesting, your team fun, and the coffee fair to middling, then
I’m interested in working with you. I’m comfortable leading teams, and can introduce an existing team to DevOps
practices, both from a technological point of view, but also from the point of view of integrating with agile practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently buzzword compatible with the existing technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puppet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redhat &amp;amp; Ubuntu Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And of course the usual basic requirements for systems administrators such as TCP networking, firewalls, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in hiring me then drop me a line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have gathered from the occasional shameless plug on this site, I’m also a writer. My first book, Puppet
Reporting and Monitoring is available from Packt Publishing. This fine tome takes you from the basics for Puppet
reporting, and explores the ways you can leverage Puppets powerful, yet almost unspoken of, reporting mechanism to
clue you into what’s going on with your infrastructure. I have two more books in development, one covering more of
the DevOps toolchain, and the other a guide for writers to implement a more realistic, and yet hardcore, view of
technology in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m available for freelance writing, and if you want me to cover topics ranging from DevOps techniques, general
technology, or industry trends for your blog, magazine or internal corporate newsletter, then feel free to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a slightly rotund chap with occasional mad hair, and a suspect beard. I live in Suffolk with my wife, daughter,
 and soon to be new baby. I ride motorbikes, fish, and spend an inordinate amount of time fixing the bits of my house that
  keep falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.io/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.io/services/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops-consultancy:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;DevOps consultancy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bespoke-development:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Bespoke Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>