<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 17:01:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.stunthamster.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Life without Puppet</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been more than six months since I&amp;rsquo;ve written, commented on, or reviewed any Puppet code. This might come as a shock
for some folk, especially those who have read my book &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; INSERT LINK &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out of the way straight away;
It&amp;rsquo;s not because I think Puppet has suddenly become awful, because that&amp;rsquo;s patently absurd. Puppet is in use in some of
the largest companies, and is enjoying explosive growth. It&amp;rsquo;s more I&amp;rsquo;ve found a tool that fits my workflow and
philospohy better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with, and hacking on, Ansible. As it turns out, Ansible addresses many of the
frustrations that I&amp;rsquo;ve had with Puppet, and allows me to be far more productive, without sacrificing any of the power of
an ideopotent configuration managment tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first major advantage of Ansible over Puppet is it&amp;rsquo;s method of connection. Puppet uses a cetnralised server that
implements it&amp;rsquo;s own certificate store. It talks over its own TCP ports, and requires a fixed server to host the Puppet
Master. The agent has to be installed on each client, and enrolled with the Puppet Master. Ansible on the other hand c
an be run from your laptop, and uses SSH to connect to the clients, generally meaning that the firewall is already open,
or at the very least, is easy to open. Becuase it uses SSH, you can use the existing techniques to manage Key pairs for
security, and it requires no agent to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a huge, huge deal when your introducing a new tool into an organisation. Many organisations I have worked in have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ease-of-use:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Ease of use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible has some of the best documentation it&amp;rsquo;s been my disctinct pleasure to come across. From the getting started guide,
through to module usage, and custom development is all detailed; this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that Puppet is any slouch when it comes
to documentation, but there are elements which are less than obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flexibility:b128b7694e4de962e0088bcb1bcb254f&#34;&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuppetDB 2.1.0 Has Been Released</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/posts/puppetdb210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/posts/puppetdb210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s July, the sun is… Well, the sun is no where in site, but at least the PuppetDB chaps have given us some summer
cheer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PuppetDB 2.1.0 has been released, and it brings some cool new features for reporting, including a feature I thought was
sorely missing, the ability to filter reports via the Puppet status (I.e. succeeded, failed). This is fantastic, as
before this you could dive into the event data to find out what failed, but couldn’t approach it from the more logical
report endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes creating your own dashboard around PuppetDB substantially easier, and means that adhoc reporting should also
be a cinch using some simple Curls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly more exciting though, is the introduction of V4 of the PuppetDB query engine. Although touted as being somewhat
of a sanity saver for the PuppetDB dev (Which is a shame, I prefer my devs a little mad), it’s also fantastic for the
end user. Up until now, support for various operators has been either lacking, or non existent for certain endpoints,
and the introduction of new endpoints has been slow. This has been in part due to the, in the words of the dev, the
disjointed code base. With query engine V4 this is now a thing of the past, and should ensure that operators and
features should start to appear much more rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/automation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;test:aa8a4255b24aebe764fdc81a33d693d7&#34;&gt;Test&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a test&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/consultancy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;consultancy:6648c37b2be70c577c139755fda219cc&#34;&gt;Consultancy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stunt Hamster speclises in&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/recruitment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-recruitment:a747c1bf9e7b4a9168ead6f9523cc51b&#34;&gt;DevOps recruitment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps engineers are in huge demand right now, but finding the right one can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/services/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;consultancy:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Consultancy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;support:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recuitment:bfc9941b6b6fd7b4ef09dd0ccd08af0c&#34;&gt;Recuitment&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/support/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-support:e39f786d0e9bcf34ce833b34fbb0c090&#34;&gt;DevOps support&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps engineers can be expensive, either as full time staff or consultants. For Startups and small companies it can
be a cost prohibitive skill to acquire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stunt Hamster offers an alternative, allowing your company access to highly skilled DevOps engineers for a fraction
 of the cost. For a monthly retainer you have full access to the skills necessary to implement DevOps concepts such as 
  Automation, monitoring and CI. You also have support for your applications and infrastructure, and advice on how to scale
  and improve your service&lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contact us now to find out how we can help you &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Stunt Hamster</title>
      <link>http://www.stunthamster.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stunthamster.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stunt Hamster is a DevOps focused consultancy, specialising in the delivery of automation, monitoring and continuous
integration. We work with clients large and small across a wide variety of industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>